Danny Page

daniel.w.page@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielwpage | https://dannypage.github.io/

Summary

Senior Software Developer and Data Engineer specializing in creating web applications to serve clients and data warehouses to support internal decision makers. I take pride in mentoring younger developers and collaborating with teammates to solve problems.

Skills

Python/Django, Ruby on Rails, Go, Javascript, SQL **Programming:** Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Oracle, SQLite

AWS Sagemaker, Tensorflow **Machine Learning:**

Other Technologies: ETL, Git/Github, Apache/Nginx, Jenkins, Chef, Airflow

Recent Work Experience

NerdWallet March 2019 - July 2022 March 2022 - July 2022 Tech Lead, Machine Learning Engineer March 2019 - March 2022 Senior Software Engineer

- Implementing features on the **Python, Flask, and PostgreSQL** stack
- Developing APIs to support Mobile and Web applications
- Using Go, Dynamo, Airflow, and AWS Sagemaker to drive our Machine Learning data pipelines
- Using Dynamo and APIs to deliver batch-insights and Sagemaker Endpoints for Real Time Insights
- Leading recruiting outreach for the NerdWallet Engineering social media accounts and blog

Upcounsel March 2018 - January 2019

Full-Stack and Data Engineer

San Francisco, CA

- Implementing features on the Ruby on Rails, MongoDB, and Backbone JS stack

- Improving database efficiency on MongoDB and PostgreSQL for ETL and data warehouse retrieval
- Creating and maintaining ETL and data processing scripts in Python
- Mentoring new employees on Git processes and Python
- Writing Automated tests for quality control with RSpec
- A/B Testing with Google Optimize and Ruby to increase user engagement and revenue
- Interviewing new candidates

Capterra (Gartner Digital Markets)

April 2016 - March 2018

Arlington, VA

Washington, DC

Full Stack Software Engineer

- Implementing features on the Ruby on Rails, Oracle, and JQuery stack
- Designing reporting suite within internal RoR app, writing SQL queries to support those reports
- Writing Automated tests for quality control with RSpec
- Managing Wordpress Blog with PHP and Rails API endpoints
- A/B Testing with Optimizely to increase user engagment and revenue

SocialCode **April 2014 - February 2016**

Back End Software Engineer

- Coded features on the **Python and Django** data platform with RedShift to build internal applications

- Implemented connections to Facebook and Twitter Advertising APIs, kept up with breaking changes
- Developed internal APIs, including creating the schema, code testing, and user feedback
- Wrote automated tests for quality control and Celery tasks for automated crawling

Translōc

January 2013 - March 2014

Fall 2019 - Fall 2020

Fall 2005 - Spring 2009

January - September 2015

Back-end Developer / Data Analyst

Raleigh, NC

- Created vehicle management features in **Python and Django**
- Structured data collection and storage in MySQL and created Transit dashboards
- Developed internal metrics to help customers identify actionable improvements for their agency
- Scaled MySQL and MongoDB databases as the company grew in scale

Education

Western Governors University

M.S. Data Analytics Remote

High Point University

B.S. Computer Science / B.S. Mathematics High Point, NC

Other Work Experience

Washington Spirit

Statistics and Technical Advisor Germantown, MD

- Collect passing and possession statistics for every game

- Creating visualizations and apps that support the coach and club's internal media in their objectives.
- Advise on technical issues that support the club's analysis and customer outreach

Data Meaning October – December 2012

Analytics Contractor

Washington, D.C. / Remote

- Consulted with clients to create **MicroStrategy** dashboards to track profits and shipping rates
- Created metrics to be measured for Monthly, Quarterly, and Yearly reports to monitor progress
- Determined correlations and forecasts using hotel customer ratings to determine future revenue

MDeverywhere, Inc.

April – October 2012

Ruby On Rails Contractor

Durham, NC

- Developed API in **Ruby on Rails** flagship application to interface with medical practices and hospitals
- Created reporting to measure insurance claim successes and determine ways to minimize rejections
- Implemented RSpec automated code testing protocols to minimize production server downtime

Knackeo June 2011 - April 2012 Raleigh, NC / Remote

Co-Founder & CEO

- Established database schema in **PostgreSQL** and developed **Ruby on Rails** application
- Continually worked with teachers and students to iterate on the design of the product
- Integrated Analytics and A/B testing to best determine conversions and adoption
- Managed team members' roles and duties to accomplish goals, oversaw front-end development

MicroStrategy

October 2010 - June 2011

Education Consultant

50% Travel / 50% Remote

- Shaped **MicroStrategy** training for various verticals including: Entertainment, Banking, Retail
- Worked with customers to determine the best metrics for success in their company
- Wrote training manuals and delivered presentations in-person and online

AOL May 2010 - September 2010

Junior Software Engineer

Sterling, VA

- Developed features for the AOL Desktop Browser in C++ and worked with QA to troubleshoot bugs

- Researched future features for further AOL Browser innovations

MicroStrategy

July 2009 - May 2010

Technical Support Engineer

McLean, VA

- Earned MicroStrategy Certified Engineer certification to architect customized reporting solutions
- Assisted customers in identifying solutions to create ideal reports and dashboards
- Documented errors for developers to accurately fix problems and enhance customer experiences